n Djerbouh

Résidence Ouarsenis, Akid Lotfi, Oran, Algeria

□+213551081911 / +31629153326 | ➡ caddydz4@gmail.com | 番 dsalim.dev | ┗ CaddyDz | ঐ salim-djerbouh |

CaddyDz | ■ saly3301



Summary

Full-stack web developer and DevOps/SysAdmin. Extensive experience in developing and maintaining large web based applications. Over six years experience specializing in backend development, infrastructure engineering, CI/CD pipelines automation. Super nerd who loves Vim, macOS, Linux, enjoys setting up and customizing development environments. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools when the need arises.

Skills

DevOps Linux, Docker, Vagrant, Sentry, Travis CI, GitHub Actions, CloudFlare, Stripe, Algolia, Pusher, Heroku, Digital Ocean and GCP

Laravel, NodeJS, MySQL, Redis, REST API Back-end

Front-end Vue.js 2/3, VueX/Pinia, Nuxt JS, WebPack, Vite, HTML5, CSS3, Vuetify Material, Bootstrap, jQuery, Jekyll, Tailwind.css

Programming PHP, Javascript ES6, C#, Python, Shell Scripting, bits of Golang and Ruby

Unit Testing QA and TDD, ACL, DAL, DTO, Modular architecture and web services Engineering

Tools Jira, ClickUp, Notion, Obsidian, VCS (Git), Swagger, Postman

Languages English, French, Arabic

Work Experience _____

Zimou Express Oran, Algeria

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER May. 2023 - Present

- Built a billing module to manage subscriptions with a dashboard and subscribable webhooks.
- · Helped the manager organize the workflow.
- Building modules integration setup for the ERP.

Upwork Remote

FREELANCE FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER Jan. 2023 - Present

- Built a full-stack webapp for a financial management platform.
- Built a multitenancy modular architecture SaaS product.
- Built a full-stack webapp for a travel agency with Laravel and Vue.

• Fixing and/or improving deployment setups for various apps.

OrderSpark Remote, USA (Freelance)

BACKEND DEVELOPER, DEVOPS LEAD

- Built management portal UI and backend (Laravel Nova)
- Built marketing site API
- Handled all DevOps infrastructure and software architecture
- Organized, secured, cleaned up and documented system resources.

One Potato, Ltd Remote, USA (Freelance)

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

- Setup a staging server/environment.
- · Redesigned the deliveries page.
- · Fixed frontend edge cases bugs.
- Refactored and cleaned up parts of the codebase to enhance maintainability.
- Developed a weekly total billing component.

American National Hockey League.

BACKEND ENGINEER, DEVOPS

- Debugging and maintaining a Django based admin panel.
- Connecting uploaded audio file briefs to AWS S3 with Amazon Alexa.
- · Maintaining deployments on Heroku.
- · Audited and mitigated unnoticed security advisories.

Oct. 2022 - Dec. 2023

Oct. 2022 - Jan. 2023

Remote, USA (Freelance)

Jan. 2022 - May. 2022

Shyfter, SRL. Brussels, Belgium

BACKEND ENGINEER, DEVOPS ASSIST

Feb. 2021 - Aug 2022

- Integrated government services with compliance to security requirements like Dimona and audited and mitigated unnoticed security advisories.
- Advised and moved the company's backend from serverless Google Cloud Run to Google dedicated servers which resulted in a faster performance and response time as well as to GitHub for a more streamlined deployment pipeline and CD productivity.
- Worked on customer exclusive features and requirements.
- Built Redis based queue system and moved long processing operations to background jobs.
- Migrated legacy codebase from pure procedural PHP to resusable service classes resulting maintainability.
- · Refactored code base reducing algorithmic complexity and also enforced coding standards for consistency.
- Built a printable dynamic GATT documents and assisted frontend team on API consumption.

Salesforce, Inc San Francisco, California

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

June. 2021 - December 2021

- · Wrote the full test-suite for Unit, Feature and Browser QA tests.
- Developed and maintained CI/CD pipeline on GitHub with actions and Heroku deployments as well as review apps on branches connecting
 everything to Jira development board.
- Audited and mitigated unnoticed security advisories.
- Eliminated bottle-neck performance issues.
- Improved managers users invite experience by building bulk CSV imports/exports.
- Improved UX by building a campaign flow saver.
- · Added a way for managers to flag users as (free access) so they don't get charged via Stripe.
- Automated fixing Salesforce branding via GitHub actions.

Zidweb, LLC. Oran, Algeria

CO-FOUNDER, CTO AND LEAD DEVELOPER

Feb. 2020 - Feb. 2021

March. 2019 - April. 2020

- Provisioned an easily manageable hybrid infrastructure(Digital Ocean Droplets + On-premise) utilizing IaC tools like Sentry and OpenVPN
- · Manage all DevOps and third party services integration (CloudFlare, Forge, Algolia, Pusher, Vonage)
- Implemented, documented RESTful API server for directory listing application
- Wrote and deployed several small scale apps like shopping carts.
- Restructured a +40 million records database of automotive spare parts catalog and implemented a web interface for it
- Created Backend in Laravel + Frontend in NuxtJS for an ELO Boosting gaming service.

Didata LLC. Zürich, Switzerland

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

• Wrote example testing data seeders for BioLab research application

- Implemented an ACL architecture for Backend API
- · Wrote mutations mapping module for state management following the Flux pattern for the Frontend application
- Implemented several CRUD models

Honors & Awards

INTERNATIONAL

2016-2023 Top %4, Overall Stack Overflow members

Amsterdam,

2018-2020 **Top #37**, PHP ranking GitHub awards

Netherlands

Presentation

GDG Conference Blida, Algeria

Presenter for <Machine Learning Theory>

Nov. 2017

- Introduced the theory of machine learning genetic algorithms with an analogy of evolutionary biology
- Introduced how machine learning algorithms work with an implementation of an SAT resolver in symbolic regression

OpenMinds Linux install party

Algiers, Algeria

SPEAKER < A LOOK INTO THE KERNEL INTERNALS>

Apr. 2017

• A brief talk about the Linux kernel source tree and subsystems with a short introduction to OSDev

Education

Lounici Ali University

Blida, Algeria

FINAL YEAR ENGLISH LITERATURE

Sep. 2013 - Jan. 2016

• American history, civilization & literature

Studied English linguistics and works of Noam Chomsky